[theme music playing]
[Ivy] How can I get what I want from her
if she doesn't trust me?
Trust can't be rushed, sweetie.
But I know ways to gain it.
Every person we let into our lives
serves a purpose, Arnaldo.
It's better that at this point,
you've already figured out
her purpose in your life.
[Ivy] Starting today,
I will befriend…
Gov. Emilia Ardiente-Torillo.
I guess Ms. Ivy's one
of the governor's friends now.
I must've had the wrong impression of her.
So, why are you stalking me?
Let's just say, to make it up to you.
Maybe I can help in your foundation.
Natalie. I'm Arnaldo's girlfriend.
[Julio] Natalie is your future.
And Ivy, she's nice
to have, but on the side.
[Carlotta] You're looking
for justice, right?
It'll take you a while
before you find evidence.
But if you're after revenge,
it's as quick as one bullet.
Hello? I have a job for you.
[man] Emilia Ardiente-Torillo,
your days are over!
-[gunshot]
-[Ivy screams]
-Gov?!
-She saved me.
[Emilia] She saved my life.
I am the pillar of Ardiente!
Someone dared to go against me!
[Ivy] Such a naughty boy, Mr. Mayor.
Does your girlfriend know about you?
[Jepoy] You weren't supposed
to hit anyone!
[man] I didn't expect her
to block the shot.
They think you're dead now.
So leave this town and never come back!
Our family is truly grateful
to you, Miss Aguas.
We are forever indebted.
You showed admirable courage.
[groans] Congressman, I just did
what was right.
You're an extraordinary woman.
[Julio] Well, should you ever
need anything…
just say so.
This house is always open to you.
Stay for as long as you like.
No, thank you. I wouldn't want to bother…
I'll only be bothered
if I let you go home
tonight in your condition.
Stay here for the night.
Please, allow us to take care of you.
Just for tonight.
Thank you, Congressman.
If you'll excuse me, I have to go.
Emilia, please take care of Miss Aguas.
Of course, Papa.
[door closing]
[Ivy groans]
I don't know where to start.
No one has ever done this for me.
Well, no one that wasn't my bodyguard.
Governor, like I said…
I only did what was right.
Thank you.
I'll forever be indebted to you…
for what you did for me.
We're family now, Ivy.
[sinister music playing]
[tense music playing]
[door opening]
[tense music continues playing]
[phone vibrating]
-Nanny Carlotta.
-Ivy!
[gasps] Ivy, I've been trying to call you.
Why weren't you answering?
I fell asleep.
The governor sent someone
here to get your clothes.
-What happened?
-I was shot.
What?!
The bullet just grazed me, though.
I'll tell you everything soon.
What's important is that I'm here now.
Ivy!
Do you think you're still
going to find anything there?
With how many years have
passed, it's near impossible.
[sighs]
I have to try first, Nanny Carlotta.
-But it's dangerous, Ivy.
-Nanny Carlotta…
When I came back here,
I prepared myself for
the danger I'd be facing.
I'll talk to you later.
-Wait for me to come back.
-Ivy, wait--
[tense music playing]
[instrumental theme music playing]
[door opening]
-Nanny.
-Diego? Where are you going?
Back home.
Why don't you leave tomorrow morning?
It's already late.
Something's bothering me.
If I don't go home
I won't be able to rest easy.
-But--
-I'll be careful.
Just go to sleep, okay?
-Take care.
-I will.
[tense music playing]
[music intensifies]
[car locking]
[door closing]
[action music playing]
[door opening]
Where have you been?
Are you really that numb?
I almost died, and you still don't care?
Emilia, can we not do this? I'm tired.
I asked you a question!
Where have you been?!
-Didn't you hear me?
-[objects shatter]
-Where'd you go?
-Are you deaf?
I said I was tired from the trip!
So stop asking questions!
-How dare you!
-Stop it.
[Emilia] I can't ask? Huh? I can't?
[Raul] Stop it! I'm not in
the mood for this.
Here's what you can do.
Why don't you just kill me…
to solve all your problems?
I'm dead to you, remember?
-After all this, huh?!
-Let go of me!
[Emilia] After all I've done for you!
Till now you still don't understand
why I did what I did for you!
You don't understand!
That I did everything because I love you!
I became a murderer
because of my love for you!
I promised myself I'd stop
killing because of you.
But you're making things difficult for me!
All you've ever done is remind me
why I shouldn't regret finishing them off!
Who are you fooling, Emilia?
Just admit that you enjoyed
getting rid of them!
That you enjoyed murdering those people!
You're heartless.
You even wiped out an entire family!
[suspenseful sting]
You had to involve an innocent child, too!
You didn't think how that affected Diego.
You killed his best friend!
[Emilia] After 13 years?
-After 13 years, Raul…
-Yes.
And we're still fighting about this?
-Yes!
-Was it my fault?! Was it mine?!
-Didn't you start all this?!
-Me?
If only you didn't take
a liking to that girl's mother,
then none of this would've happened!
Her father wouldn't have gone against us!
Did you think that girl wouldn't know?
That she wouldn't accuse me?!
It's just a choice between her and me!
What if she ruins our family?
I won't allow her to!
That's why it's good
they're all done with!
I will kill anyone
who dares ruin the family I've supported
and everything we've worked for!
I won't allow it!
And I've done all this because I love you!
Why can't you stop being unfaithful?
Is that too much to ask?
For you to love me? Is it so hard?
How can I love a murderer like you?
What? Go on!
[Raul] Does the truth hurt?
[Emilia wails]
You've killed so many people.
Now, I'm going to kill you.
I can kill you, too, Raul.
-Not if I kill you first!
-You bastard!
-I hate you!
-You piece of trash!
Murderer!
-Monster!
-Let go
-I'll kill you!
-I'll kill you first!
[Raul] I'll kill you first!
Do you understand?!
-You bastard!
-Dad!
-Dad, stop!
-[Emilia grunts]
[Raul] Murderer.
Dad, what's going on?
Dad, stop this. Whatever Mom's fault is,
you don't have the right to hurt her.
[Raul] Fine, side with her.
I don't even understand why
I still come home to this house.
We both know why!
Because you want even a little
of the power the Ardientes have.
But you will never be an Ardiente!
You're just a leech!
-A leech!
-Mom, stop.
-You're not going to stop, are you?
-You leech!
-Dad, stop.
-You just can't shut up, huh?
-Come here.
-Dad, please, stop this.
Let go of me.
We're not done yet, Emilia.
[tense music playing]
-Mom?
-[Emilia weeps]
Mom, don't cry.
Emilia, you murderer.
You murderer.
-Didn't you…
-Me?
[Emilia] …start all this?!
If only you didn't take
a liking to that girl's mother,
her father wouldn't have gone against us.
You bitch. You monster.
[Raul] You enjoyed murdering those people.
You wiped out an entire family!
You didn't think
-how that affected Diego.
-[gunshot]
You killed his best friend!
You're all monsters.
All of you.
[tires screeching]
What's your problem?!
-You're my problem!
-What?!
-Were you going to kill me?
-Run me off the road?! Kill me, too?
-What did you want me to do?!
You were driving so fast!
-Monsters!
-Ivy.
They're all monsters!
Murderers!
The Ardientes are all monsters!
-Calm down. Calm down.
-[Ivy sobbing]
They're monsters.
Damn you, Emilia!
The Ardientes should all burn in hell!
[weeping]
Calm down.
[Carlotta] Have some water, dear.
Please, Ivy.
[somber music playing]
I knew it, Nanny Carlotta.
I knew she was the mastermind.
But it's different…
hearing her say that…
she had my father killed.
And my mother, too.
I thought I already knew
that family enough…
because of the documents you sent me.
But…
I was wrong.
Whenever I see them…
I can't help but remember
what they did to my parents.
Don't worry, Ivy.
We'll locate where your mother is buried.
I already found the hit man Emilia hired.
He's alive.
[Jepoy] You'll avenge your mother.
Just give me some time.
[somber music playing]
[somber music continues playing]
[sentimental music playing]
-[young Lily] Hey, let go of me!
-Come on.
-Let go of me!
-[whistles]
If you're in trouble, blow this.
I'm the parking boy! Jepoy.
[Berto] You think you're tough? Hit here!
-He thinks he's tough!
-[whistles]
The cops! Run!
[police officer]
You two, chase after them!
Stand up! Are you hurt?
-Here, eat up.
-You know what?
I thought I was done for
because of Berto or the cops.
Plus, I was starving!
You're like an angel.
Don't mention it.
Ms. Prianka and I
were supposed to head somewhere,
but then we saw you getting beaten up.
I just spoke to her,
and she'll help you
and pay for your education.
She said you can stay
at her house in the province.
That's okay, right?
Right? Hey!
Hey! [giggles]
Hey, that's fine, right?
[sentimental music playing]
[no audible dialogue]
This is Madrigal.
My most trusted man. He'll accompany us.
-[gunshot]
-[Emilia screams]
[screaming] Were you
going to kill me, too?
Calm down.
[sentimental music continues playing]
I'll protect you.
I'll never leave your side.
Whatever happens, I won't leave you.
[somber music playing]
[exhales sharply]
Hey, Jepoy, where's Ivy?
She's still sleeping in her room.
Ah…
-Uh, Nanny Carlotta.
-Yes?
I'll set up security cameras around, okay?
And add locks on the doors.
It's too easy to break into this house.
Jepoy…
I know the two of us are here
because we both love her.
So, please…
take care of Ivy.
Let's hope nothing bad happens to her.
Nanny Carlotta, you don't have
to tell me that.
You know I owe Ivy my life, right?
I'll do everything and anything for her.
Thank you.
-[knocking on door]
-[door opening]
Ivy, good--
Did Ivy leave? Without saying goodbye?
It seems she left last night, Papa.
But Arnaldo will call her.
By the way, give me a copy
of the information we got about her.
I want to see how many
properties and assets she owns.
I want to know just how much
she can contribute to the Ardientes.
Yes, Papa.
Now.
Have some coffee, dear.
Jepoy, come eat!
[Carlotta] Take a seat.
[tense music playing]
Ivy, how's your wound?
I know…
Don't worry. It won't happen again.
-Jepoy, have some bread.
-Thank you.
You know what?
The old man's biding his time.
I'm sure he hasn't forgotten
about the shooting attempt on Emilia.
You need to lie low, Ivy.
Divert their attention
while I look for your mother.
[tense music playing]
Let me, Ivy. Here's some toast.
[sinister music playing]
[Julio] Hmm…
Oh. [chuckles]
NET WORTH: 1.54 BILLION USD
This can be an ace up my sleeve.
All her wealth…
Make sure we'll get all of it, Emilia.
Yes, Papa.
Hmm.
You can eat now.
[laughs viciously]
NATIONAL CRIMINAL BACKGROUND CHECK
[sinister music playing]
[Jepoy] You need to lie low, Ivy.
Divert their attention
while I look for your mother.
[line ringing]
-[phone ringing]
-You left your phone, dear.
-Arnaldo is calling you.
-[phone ringing]
Thank you.
-Mr. Mayor?
You left without saying goodbye.
Your family has done so much for me.
I didn't want to overstay my welcome.
[Arnaldo] What are you talking about?
We're the ones who are indebted to you.
Mr. Mayor, did you call for a reason,
or did you just want to hear my voice?
Uh, well…
I wanted to invite you to breakfast.
I made you breakfast in bed. And also…
I want to talk to you about
the export processing zone.
To make your family
even more indebted to me?
Ah…
-[chuckles]
-[scoffs]
Mr. Mayor, why do I feel
like I made you blush?
[chuckles]
I was just kidding.
Consider my investment done.
Really?
Like what your mother, the governor, said,
we're family now.
Wow. Wow.
I… I don't know what to say.
Are we clear about my plans, Mr. Fernan?
I'll try to convince them.
Mr. Fernan…
You know that this will
benefit the entire town.
It'll improve everyone's lives.
The investors are ready
for this project, Mr. Fernan.
But, Mayor, many people
will lose their land.
Of course we have to make sacrifices.
But it's for…
the prosperity of everyone in this town.
[scoffs]
You're the first person I notified
because you are the
president of the cooperative.
[Arnaldo] I know you're capable
of understanding this project,
for the whole town.
Because, just like me,
you're a leader, too.
Can I count on you, Mr. Fernan?
[sighs]
[Pandoy] Come on, Fernan.
It's not that simple!
The cooperative will lose all the land!
Is that what you're trying to say?!
That's what we call "sacrifice," Pandoy!
[slams table] Hold it!
-Why do we have to sacrifice?
-That's right!
Did the mayor sacrifice anything for us?
-You don't get it.
We will all benefit
from the export processing zone!
How? Tell us, how?!
[Fernan] We're going to get jobs!
[Loring] It's not that simple, Fernan!
We have jobs!
[Fernan] They're not
going to take our land!
We need to expand our
understanding, and not just…
-…get stuck farming.
-What are you saying?
-That we're narrow-minded?!
-Yes!
[Fernan] We have to widen our perspective!
[Pandoy] Can you even
hear what you're saying?!
What's happening here?
It's the mayor.
He wants to build an export zone here,
on the land owned by the cooperative!
Your brother's acting
like a greedy Ardiente again!
And that Ivy, the woman who visited us?
She's one of them! She's an investor!
-That's right.
-Hey, wait.
You're getting too personal, Loring.
The Ardientes have been working
so hard to improve our lives!
Right? Diego's proof of that!
-There.
-Diego.
And you proved that you don't
understand the situation
-of the rest of us!
-But this is…
Hold up. Hold up.
-…all for us.
-Hold up. Hold up.
Everyone, calm down.
Let's stop arguing.
You'll keep your land.
I assure you.
-We hope so.
-That's where we get our crops.
-It's all we have.
-I hope…
We hope you can help us, Diego.
[woman] We've stayed here for so long.
-We can't get another job.
-What about our kids?
I'll take care of this.
They're willing to let go
of their land, just like that?
[chuckles]
Ms. Aguas…
are you doubting my
ability to convince people?
As long as you assure me,
Mr. Mayor, that it will
not inconvenience them.
Of course.
You have my word.
[sinister music playing]
-[tearing check]
-Here.
[sinister music playing]
TWENTY-FIVE MILLION PESOS ONLY
I want to host a fundraising
dinner for the congressman.
Fundraiser?
I just thought that, since
I've invested a huge amount
on the export processing zone,
I want to make sure the
Ardientes will keep it running.
So, I might as well go all the way.
For our success.
[sinister music continues playing]
["Sa'Yo" instrumental playing]
[sighs]
Arnaldo!
Who gave you the right
to take the cooperative's lot?
You're heartless!
Calm down, bro.
You know…
No one's taking anything.
In fact, you should thank me.
Because those peasants will be
compensated appropriately.
I did it for them.
For Poblacion Ardiente!
Hold on. Why are you so angry?
They aren't complaining.
Relax, Diego.
Stress is bad for the heart.
[Arnaldo whistles]
[suspenseful music playing]
-Tonyo.
-[cocks gun]
I need some information.
[Camia] Please stay away from me!
Please… Go away!
Lily… Run!
Shut up!
-No!
-[gunshot]
[phone ringing]
Jepoy?
Ivy, I know where they buried your mother.
You do? Where?
Jepoy, where are you? I'm going there!
Don't. Stay there.
You still have to meet the Ardientes.
No, Jepoy. I'll go there!
I don't care about the
Ardientes! Where are you?!
Ivy.
You have to face them or
your plans will be ruined.
Bring me my mother. Bring her back home.
Bring her here.
Bring her back to me.
Diego, why aren't you getting ready yet?
-What?
-Everyone at the market
was talking about the huge
party at Ms. Ivy's mansion.
Aren't you going?
Her invitation was just a formality.
I don't need to be there.
But you should still go.
What if they discuss the cooperative?
Shouldn't at least one of us
be there to hear it?
-Is Dad going to the party?
-Of course!
He won't pass up this chance
to meet prominent people,
including the beautiful girls there.
Your dad wouldn't miss it.
You know how he is.
He dabbles in politics.
And he wants to run
for the local elections.
[exhales]
About Ivy, by the way,
be careful around her.
After she saved your life,
you still have doubts about her.
She's even helping Grandpa,
and she doesn't have to.
-[scoffs]
-And wait a second.
I thought you saw her as family.
Hmm…
That conversation was
supposed to be private.
Why did she mention that?
Son, all I'm saying is…
we don't know her that well.
She's not part of our world.
She's a total stranger!
I'm not sure if she's
showing us her true colors.
That's all I'm worried about.
So… Let's go?
Let's go to the party for your grandpa.
[tense music playing]
[music intensifies]
[subtle music playing]
[sobbing]
Where's my mother?
I told you to bring her to me.
Why didn't you bring her to me?
She's in a safe place.
I can't bring her body here.
It's too risky.
-Ivy…
-[Ivy weeps]
Ivy, calm down.
You can't let the Ardientes
suspect anything.
The Ardientes?
They're monsters.
That mayor…
the governor…
and the congressman.
I'll take them all down one by one.
All of them. All the Ardientes!
They'll pay.
[Carlotta] Ivy? Sweetie.
The Ardientes are here.
[sinister music playing]
-[jazz music playing]
-[indistinct chatter]
Stop being so obvious
about wanting this house.
It's going to be ours.
We'll use her.
And bleed her dry.
Just like the last owner of this house.
[Natalie] Arnaldo. Hi.
-Hi, Auntie.
-Hello.
Hello. Hello.
-Hi.
-Good evening.
Good evening.
Good evening, Uncle.
[Natalie] What an amazing house.
Ivy's house is beautiful.
Is Diego coming?
I don't know where he is.
[woman] Ladies and gentlemen,
may I have your attention, please?
Ms. Ivy Aguas is on her way down.
Please.
[tense music playing]
[tense music continues playing]
[sinister music playing]
[guests clapping]
[music intensifies]
I want you to remember my face.
I'll bring you down one by one
till you're begging for mercy…
and the sweet reprise of death.
Just like how you murdered my family.
Just like how my mother begged for mercy.
I am Ivy Aguas.
And I am vengeance.
[sinister music playing]
Sometimes, it's so hard being honest.
[Ivy] You're right, Governor.
Like with men. They cheat so blatantly.
My boyfriend is not a book nor is he a toy
that can be borrowed or shared.
[Ivy] You can have Arnaldo.
I like my toys brand new.
-[screams]
-[objects shatter]
[Diego] Ma.
You've got the skin
of a crocodile, Governor.
[Emilia] I shall see you tomorrow.
And don't worry, my maids
won't spill coffee on you.
[Ivy] I invested a lot. That
means I'll reap something bigger
in return.
[theme music playing]